saddahaq.com 2017-02-06

# Privacy & Security Policy

Viven Infomedia Private Limited ("Viven" or "Company") owns and operates https://www.saddahaq.com and a variety of sub-sites and micro-sites therein, which is an online news portal. The services offered by Viven (the "Services") includes the Uniform Resource Locator – https://www.saddahaq.com (the "Website") and any other graphics, layout, text, instructions, images, audio, videos, designs, features, content, or applications offered from time to time by Viven on the Website. 

This Privacy and Security Policy ("Policy") applies to the Services offered by Viven. This Policy describes Viven's use and sharing of information received from persons accessing or using the Services ("User") whether he/she is a "Visitor" (which means that User simply browses the Website, or otherwise uses the Services without being registered with Viven) or is a "Member" (which means that User has registered with Viven). Viven adheres to the applicable laws regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information. 

Viven's Policy is subject to change at any time without notice. The User shall review the Policy periodically to make sure that he/she is aware of any changes to it. The User agrees to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Policy while accessing the Website. If User does not agree with the terms and conditions of the Policy, he/she should not use or access the Website. 

The Policy is incorporated into "Terms of Use" and is subject to the terms laid down therein. 

* Information Collected from User 

**1.1.** When User registers with Viven or uses the Services, Viven may ask the User to provide information such as: (1) personally identifiable information, which includes any information about the User that could reasonably be used to identify him/her in person, such as the User's name, address, email address, date of birth or phone number ("Personal Information"), and (2) information relating to any communication that the User may have with Viven or any other User using any of the Services offered on the Website such as e-mails, chat room, discussion boards, IM communications, forum communications, membership on mailing lists, etc. ("Communication Information"). 

**1.2.** 1.2. In addition to any Personal Information that User chooses to submit to Viven, Viven and its third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) collect certain information, including but not limited to usernames, passwords, and other security related information in relation to the usage of the Website, whenever User visits or utilizes the Services ( **"Usage Information"** ). Viven automatically receives and records information that User's browser sends whenever User visits the Website. Further, these server logs may include information such as User's IP address or a unique identifier ( **"Device Identifier"** ), browser type, browser language, the date and time of User's request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify User's browser from his/her computer or other device used to access the Services ("Device"). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to User's Device used to access the Services, and Viven's computers identify User's Device by its Device Identifier. 

**1.3.** Cookies (data file placed on a Device when it is used to access the Services) may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering User and User's preferences and tracking User's visits to the Website. Viven uses temporary and permanent cookies when User signs in, to identify him/her and keep track of his/her personal session. All such information is securely stored, and no Personal Information is stored on User's cookie. If User chooses to disable the cookies on his/her Device, some features of the Services may not function properly. If User chooses to allow the cookies on his/her Device, User is hereby permitting Viven to use the Information collected by the cookies. 

**1.4.** Viven uses aggregate data collected in log files and cookies to enhance or otherwise improve the Services, ascertain User's preference, to customize the advertising and content User sees, retrieval of information already provided by the User on the Website, improve the Services, develop new services, conduct research, etc. These cookies and log files do not store User’s Personal Information, but they are tied to User's Personal Information in Viven's system. 

**1.5.** Viven uses session ID cookies to make it easier for User to navigate through the Website. Session ID cookies expire upon one week of inactivity or when User closes his/her browser whichever is shorter. Viven also uses a persistent cookie that remains on User's hard drive for an extended period of time, so that Viven can recognize such User when he/she returns to the Website. 

**1.6.** Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as **"1x1GIFs"** or **"clearGIFs"** ) may be present on the Website. Web beacons may be invisible to the User, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into the Website can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count Users of the Services, to monitor how Users navigate the Services, to count how many sent e-mails were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a User's computer hard drive, clearGIFs are embedded invisibly on the Website. Viven does not tie web beacons to Personal Information. 

**1.7.** Further, a programming code that is designed to collect information about User's interactions with the Services ( **"Embedded Script"** ) is temporarily downloaded onto User’s Device from Viven's web server. However, such Embedded Script is active only while User is connected to the Services, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter. 

**1.8.** Any User accessing or using the Website from any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, protection and disclosure, that differ from Indian laws, understands and accepts that through his/her continued use of the Services, he/she is transferring his/her personal information to India and he/she consents to that transfer in compliance with the legal provisions on the subject matter as applicable in India, in addition to the Terms of Use and this Policy. 

* Use of such Information Collected 

**2.1.** Viven will use Personal Information and Communication Information collected from Users to deliver the Services requested through the Website, Viven's social networking accounts including, but not limited to facebook, twitter, pinterest and foursquare accounts, enhance the operations of the Website, improve Viven's marketing and promotional efforts, analyze Website use, improve Viven's Service offerings, inform Users about online and offline services, updates, and to tailor User's experience with third parties. For example, if User sends Viven's customer service an email we may use User’s comments and feedback to tell others about Viven’s services, and may post User's comment in Viven's marketing materials or on the Website. Viven may also use the Personal Information to troubleshoot, resolve disputes, accomplish administrative tasks, contact User, enforce Viven's agreements with User including Website's Terms of Use and this Policy, comply with applicable laws, and cooperate with law enforcement activities. 

**2.2.** Viven shall use the Personal Information for collecting and analysing the demographic and profile data of the Website's User and such User's activity on the Website. Personal Information and Usage Information may be used by Viven to ensure that the Services and the Website are available at all times to the User. Such information may also be used by Viven for gathering demographic information by way of occasional online surveys. 

* Disclosure of Personal Information 

**3.1.** Viven does not rent, sell or share Personal Information it collects about User to or with third parties unless consent of the Users have been obtained in this regard, and Personal Information collected from User is only used to provide him/her with the Services and to comply with any requirements of law. 

**3.2.** Viven's agents or contractors may have access to User's Personal Information for the purpose of performing Services on behalf of Viven. All such agents or contractors who have access to User's Personal Information are required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the Services they are performing for Viven or as otherwise required by law. 

**3.3.** Viven may share Personal Information with its other corporate entities and affiliates to detect and prevent identity theft, fraud and other potentially illegal acts; and correlate related or multiple accounts to prevent abuse of Viven's Services. 

**3.4.** Viven may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to summons, court orders , or other legal process. Viven may disclose User's Personal Information to law enforcement offices, third party rights owners, or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce Viven’s Terms or this Policy, respond to claims of violation of the rights of a third party in relation to any advertisement, posting or other content, or protect the rights, property or personal safety of Users or the public at large. 

**3.5.** Further, if Viven should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company or sell its assets, Viven may sell or transfer the information User provided to Viven on this Website to a third party or share User's Personal Information to the company with which Viven enters into such transaction. 

* Security of Information Collected from Users 

**4.1.** Viven works continuously to protect the privacy and security of User's Personal Information. Viven updates and tests its technology regularly to ensure that it maintains commercially reasonable standards in securing User's privacy. Viven maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect User's Personal Information. Viven has designed its systems to ensure that passwords and any other access codes are always private and confidential. For User protection, only Users have knowledge about their access codes. In addition, User's Personal Information resides on secure server(s) to which only selected personnel and contractors have access. Viven encrypts sensitive information using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure that User's Personal and Financial Information is safe as it is transmitted to it. 

* Links to Other Websites 

**5.1.** The Website links to other websites that may collect User's Personal Information. Viven is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those linked websites. 

* Grievance Officer 

**6.1.** In accordance with Information Technology Act, 2000 and Rules made there under, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer are provided below: 

Name: Mr. Pallav Bajjuri  
Mailing Address: Shubhodaya Towers, 5th Floor, Plot 8, Alakapuri, Nagole, Hyderabad –  
500068, Telangana, India.  
Phone Number: 040 - 64552727  
Email address: legal [at] saddahaq [dot] com  

* Communication 

**7.1.** If User has any questions or concerns regarding privacy at the Website, please send Viven a detailed message at **legal [at] saddahaq [dot] com**
